<?xml version="1.0"?>
<games>
  <game>
    <name>Shisen-Seki</name>
    <short>A game of Shisen-Sho</short>
    <icon>game_128.png</icon>
    <link>Shisen-Seki.opk</link>
    <preview>shisen01.png</preview>
    <date>Monday, 28 Dec 2015</date>
    <author>Artur Rojek (zear), Joe Vargas (jxv)</author>
    <portauthor/>
    <homepage>https://github.com/zear/shisen-seki</homepage>
    <description>Shisen-Seki (四川石) is a game of Shisen-Sho - a classic japanese logic game utilizing Mahjong stones.<br/> <br/> The goal of Shisen-Sho is to remove all stones from the board. Do so by matching pairs of stones with the same face.<br/> You can only match stones if they can be joined by 3 or less lines. Each line must be either horizontal or vertical and can't cross other stones on the board.<br/> <br/> Not all games are solvable.<br/> <br/> Game modes:<br/> * Classic - classic Shisen-Sho rules.<br/> * Gravity - after clearing two matching stones, remaining stones in the column will move down and fill the empty space.<br/> <br/> Authors:<br/> * Programming &amp; fonts - Artur Rojek (zear)<br/> * Graphics - Joe Vargas (jxv)<br/> <br/> License:<br/> * Source code - MIT License<br/> * Graphics - CC0 1.0 Universal<br/> * Fonts - CC0 1.0 Universal<br/> * Music/Sfx:<br/> * "White Lotus" by Kevin MacLeod (incompetech.com) - Creative Commons: By Attribution 3.0; Changes: Trimmed and converted to OGG<br/> * "Short wind sound" by remaxim -CC0 1.0 Universal; Changes: Tempo changes<br/> <br/> Changelog:<br/> v0.2.0 (2015/12/24)<br/> * Original game release</description>
  </game>
  <game>
    <name>Hase</name>
    <short>Worms-style shooter featuring bunnies</short>
    <icon>game_128.png</icon>
    <link>hase.opk</link>
    <preview>hase_screenshot_gcw_ingame3.png</preview>
    <date>Wednesday, 18 Nov 2015</date>
    <author>Ziz</author>
    <portauthor/>
    <homepage>http://ziz.gp2x.de</homepage>
    <description>Hase is a Worms-inspired, turn-based artillery game, that comes with a twist - the gameplay takes place in space, where each piece of the level has it's own gravitational field, influencing the missile trajectories and player movement. This time however, it's not earthworms, but hares, who take place of the troopers shooting each other, making use of 16 creative weapons.<br/> <br/> Hase comes with a local Hot-Seat mode, allowing for multiple people sharing the same console play against each other or AI opponents. The game features also an Online mode, letting you play with other GCW Zero users around the world.<br/> <br/> So go ahead, try Hase for GCW Zero and join the striving community of avid rabbit-shooters.</description>
  </game>
  <game>
    <name>Oswan</name>
    <short>WonderSwan emulator</short>
    <icon>emulator_128.png</icon>
    <link>oswan.opk</link>
    <preview>oswan.png</preview>
    <date>Wednesday, 18 Nov 2015</date>
    <author>bird_may_nike, alekmaul</author>
    <portauthor>Gameblabla</portauthor>
    <homepage>https://github.com/gameblabla/oswan</homepage>
    <description>Gameblabla's Oswan is a WonderSwan/WonderSwan Color emulator based on Oswan.<br/> It was especially made in mind for GCW0 and has several features such as support for savestates, different input layouts and more.</description>
  </game>
  <game>
    <name>Fruit'Y</name>
    <short>Playing with edibles</short>
    <icon>game_128.png</icon>
    <link>fruity_v1.00.opk</link>
    <preview>fruity_1.png</preview>
    <date>Saturday, 07 Nov 2015</date>
    <author>Retroguru</author>
    <portauthor>Artur "zear" Rojek</portauthor>
    <homepage>http://www.retroguru.com/fruity/</homepage>
    <description>Fruit'Y is a puzzle game heavily inspired by the Kaiko classic “Gem'X”, known from the Commodore Amiga 500, Commodore 64 and Atari ST.<br/> <br/> In this game, you help a little Sheran morph fruits on the left side of the screen in order to reproduce the composition on the right side and proceed to the next level.</description>
  </game>
  <game>
    <name>Meteoroid3D</name>
    <short>Stereoscopic arcade 3D shooter.</short>
    <icon>game_128.png</icon>
    <link>meteoroid3d.opk</link>
    <preview>meteoroid3d.png</preview>
    <date>Sunday, 20 Sep 2015</date>
    <author>Ziz</author>
    <portauthor/>
    <homepage>https://github.com/theZiz/meteoroid3d</homepage>
    <description>Meteoroid3D is a stereoscopic 3D shooter in the spirit of Asteroids.<br/> <br/> Feature list:<br/> * Stereoscopic graphics with settings for red-green, red-cyan, red-blue or yellow-blue glasses. Of course you can play without 3d glasses, too, but then you will not enjoy the incredible DEPTH of the game! (Furthermore it is really easier to hit the meteoroids with 3D glasses...)<br/> * 3 different kinds of meteoroids. There are not only different in size, they are also different in points you get and in the number of sub meteoroids they will split!<br/> * Endless world - if you reach the end, another identical world will appear!<br/> * Awesome public domain music from Kevin MacLeod<br/> * Incredible realistic laser animation and sounds!<br/> * High end particle effects!<br/> * Total unconfusing 3D map!<br/> * Of course C4A support from the very beginning.</description>
  </game>
  <game>
    <name>Super Transball 2</name>
    <short>"Thrust" style arcade game</short>
    <icon>game_128.png</icon>
    <link>stransball2_r1.opk</link>
    <preview>stransball2_2.png</preview>
    <date>Sunday, 12 Jul 2015</date>
    <author>Santi Ontañón Villar</author>
    <portauthor>Artur "zear" Rojek</portauthor>
    <homepage>https://github.com/zear/stransball2</homepage>
    <description>Super Transball 2 is an enhanced version of TRANSBALL 2, which is the sequel of TRANSBALL, a remake of the classic THRUST game (but mainly inspired in ZARA THRUSTA for the Commodore Amiga 500).<br/> <br/> In each level the goal is to find the white sphere, and carry it to the upper part of the screen. This may seem easy at the begining, but as the levels become more and more complicated, to reach the top of the screen can be extremely difficult...<br/> <br/> Story:<br/> The future, the sun does not shine anymore and the only energy source are 'the spheres'. The spheres contain enough energy for a planet to survive. they are charged with the energy of other stars.<br/> As the humans are highly dependent on the spheres, an oportunist civilization has stolen all the charged spheres from the earth expecting to colonize the planet. As a last chance, the last energy has been transfered to a scout ship and sent to recover the spheres...<br/> <br/> You command this ship, you are the last chance for the survival of the human race...</description>
  </game>
  <game>
    <name>Sissi</name>
    <short>An IRC client</short>
    <icon>application_128.png</icon>
    <link>sissi.opk</link>
    <preview>sissi.png</preview>
    <date>Friday, 12 Jun 2015</date>
    <author>Ziz</author>
    <portauthor/>
    <homepage>http://ziz.gp2x.de/</homepage>
    <description>Sissi is a client for IRC - Internet Relay Chat.</description>
  </game>
  <game>
    <name>uHexen 2</name>
    <short>A dark fantasy FPS game by Raven Software</short>
    <icon>game_128.png</icon>
    <link>hexen2.opk</link>
    <preview></preview>
    <date>Friday, 12 Jun 2015</date>
    <author>Raven Software</author>
    <portauthor>JohnnyonFlame</portauthor>
    <homepage>https://github.com/JohnnyonFlame</homepage>
    <description>A fantasy game set in a dark world, Hexen 2 is an FPS game presented to you by Raven Software and published by iD Software, and is the third installment in the Serpent Riders trilogy.<br/> <br/> Installation instructions:<br/> Copy the data1/ folder from Hexen 2 CD into ~/.hexen2 on your GCW Zero, then make sure to delete any .cfg files from the new data1/ location.<br/> <br/> uHexen2 is compatible with both the full and shareware versions of the game.</description>
  </game>
  <game>
    <name>Falling Time</name>
    <short>Guide a falling ball through blocks. Avoid getting crushed!</short>
    <icon>game_128.png</icon>
    <link>falling_time.opk</link>
    <preview>fallingtime.png</preview>
    <date>Sunday, 17 May 2015</date>
    <author>cxong, Nebuleon, Gab1975 and others</author>
    <portauthor/>
    <homepage>https://github.com/cxong/FallingTime</homepage>
    <description>Falling Time, a simple arcade game where you control a ball and fall through gaps as long as you can, before the top of the screen catches up to you!<br/> <br/> Formerly known as ativayeban.<br/> <br/> Features:<br/> * Local multiplayer, left hand vs right hand!<br/> * Award-winning music<br/> * Chipmunk 2D physics<br/> * D-pad, analog or G-sensor control (use up/down to switch)<br/> * Eggplants<br/> <br/> Thanks to Nebuleon for the original concept, Gab1975 for the graphics, and everyone who helped!</description>
  </game>
  <game>
    <name>Nampure</name>
    <short>Classic Number Place game, also known as Sudoku®</short>
    <icon>game_128.png</icon>
    <link>nampure-0.5.opk</link>
    <preview>nampure-gameplay.png</preview>
    <date>Sunday, 17 May 2015</date>
    <author>Jeremy (Remjey) Farnaud</author>
    <portauthor/>
    <homepage>http://jf.almel.fr/nampure/</homepage>
    <description>A classic number puzzle game in the form of a incomplete grid of numbers with missing values that you must discover using a set of rules that ensure there is only one valid solution.</description>
  </game>
  <game>
    <name>Meritous</name>
    <short>An action-adventure dungeon crawl game.</short>
    <icon>game_128.png</icon>
    <link>meritous_r1.opk</link>
    <preview>meritous_1.png</preview>
    <date>Saturday, 16 May 2015</date>
    <author>Lancer-X/Asceai</author>
    <portauthor>Artur "zear" Rojek (w/ patches by Nebuleon &amp; David Knight)</portauthor>
    <homepage>https://github.com/zear/meritous</homepage>
    <description>MERITOUS is a top-view dungeon crawl action/adventure game.<br/> As MERIT, a PSI user, your task is to investigate the Orcus Dome, an ancient underground shrine.<br/> <br/> In your way are the shadowy creatures that wander the shrine. Using your PSI circuit, you must cut through any that come between you and your goal.<br/> <br/> Default controls:<br/> * D-PAD/JOY - Move around. To walk through doors, simply walk up to them and push against them.<br/> * A - Charge your PSI circuit.<br/> * L - View the map (you can then use the D-PAD/JOY to scroll around the map.<br/> * R - View the help file.<br/> * START - Activate a trigger tile that you are standing on. START is also used for various other things, such as for reading in-game dialogue.<br/> * SELECT - Pause/Exit the game.<br/> <br/> Changelog:<br/> 2015/05/16 - release #1<br/> * Adjust the game interface to the 320x240 resolution.<br/> * Optimize the save format (Nebuleon)<br/> * Remove music files due to ambiguous license status<br/> <br/> Bugs:<br/> Such a vast game like Meritous is very difficult to debug and test properly. Below is a list of known issues, to be addressed in future releases:<br/> * Boss room doors on the minimap view have corrupted graphics.<br/> * "Complete Map" artifact doesn't seem to be working.<br/> * Different zoom levels of the minimap are not available.<br/> <br/> If you have found any other issues in the game - please let me know.</description>
  </game>
  <game>
    <name>L'Abbaye des Morts</name>
    <short>Adventure game inspired by classic ZX-Spectrum titles.</short>
    <icon>game_128.png</icon>
    <link>abbaye.opk</link>
    <preview>abbaye-img.png</preview>
    <date>Thursday, 14 May 2015</date>
    <author>Locomalito and David Lara</author>
    <portauthor>Dmitry Smagin</portauthor>
    <homepage>https://github.com/dmitrysmagin/abbaye-des-morts</homepage>
    <description>This game is about a medieval French monk who is hiding in an old church not knowing that ancient evil lies beneath it. Graphics and gameplay are done in the style of classic ZX-Spectrum exploration games, although a version with modernized graphics is available.</description>
  </game>
  <game>
    <name>Ri-li</name>
    <short>Pick up the coaches, but don't wreck the train!</short>
    <icon>game_128.png</icon>
    <link>Ri-li.opk</link>
    <preview>ri-li.png</preview>
    <date>Saturday, 28 Mar 2015</date>
    <author>Dominique Roux-Serret</author>
    <portauthor>David Knight</portauthor>
    <homepage>http://ri-li.sourceforge.net/download.html</homepage>
    <description>Ri-li is a game in which you control the path of a wooden engine around a track by changing points. The aim is to pick up all the coaches around the track without collision.</description>
  </game>
  <game>
    <name>Handy</name>
    <short>Atari Lynx emulator</short>
    <icon>emulator_128.png</icon>
    <link>handy.opk</link>
    <preview>handy.png</preview>
    <date>Saturday, 28 Mar 2015</date>
    <author>Keith Wilkins</author>
    <portauthor>David Knight</portauthor>
    <homepage>https://github.com/DavidKnight247/handy320-rzx50</homepage>
    <description>Handy for the GCW0 console is based on the original Dingux port by d_smagin with several enhancements.<br/> <br/> Handy supports zipped roms, savestates and hardware scaling. It can display numerous border images and scanlines.<br/> <br/> Handy requires a Lynx bios image to run. Instructions on where to put this are in the manual or they will be displayed on screen if no bios is found.</description>
  </game>
  <game>
    <name>JzIntellivision</name>
    <short>Intellivision emulator</short>
    <icon>emulator_128.png</icon>
    <link>jzIntv.opk</link>
    <preview>jzIntv.png</preview>
    <date>Saturday, 21 Mar 2015</date>
    <author>Joe Zbiciak</author>
    <portauthor>David Knight</portauthor>
    <homepage>https://github.com/DavidKnight247/jzIntv</homepage>
    <description>jzIntellivision is an Intellivision emulator with support for user created overlays and virtual keyboard. There is also a configuration utility which expands the list of compatible games to almost every title available for the system.<br/> <br/> HOW TO PLAY<br/> You will need an intellivison bios rom set in order to play any games. These are legally obtainable from the Intellivision Lives! CD for Windows/Mac for example, which also contains a selection of games. Place them in the $HOME/.jzintellivision/bios folder which autocreates on the first run. The names of the bios files should be:<br/> <br/> grom.bin<br/> exec.bin<br/> <br/> (and also optionally)<br/> game.rom<br/> ecs.bin<br/> <br/> Game roms can be placed anywhere, the rom chooser will remember the last used rom location.<br/> <br/> CONTROLS (Available to view from the menu)<br/> D-pad: Directional disc<br/> A: Top fire button<br/> X: Left fire button<br/> Y: Right fire button<br/> B: Enter<br/> L: Show keyboard<br/> R: Show numberpad<br/> SELECT: Menu<br/> START: Toggle player 1/2 controls</description>
  </game>
  <game>
    <name>The Ur-Quan Masters</name>
    <short>An inter-galatic adventure game.</short>
    <icon>game_128.png</icon>
    <link>uqm-2014-11-23.opk</link>
    <preview>uqm.png</preview>
    <date>Sunday, 15 Mar 2015</date>
    <author>Toys For Bob, UQM team</author>
    <portauthor>soulsource</portauthor>
    <homepage>http://sc2.sf.net/</homepage>
    <description>For the past decade, Earth and the rest of the Alliance of Free Stars has fought the Ur-Quan and their Hierarchy of Battle Thralls. In the course of the War, the Earthlings discovered a factory world by the 'Precursors' - an impossibly advanced that disappeared tens of thousands of years ago. This colony, Unzervalt (aka Vela I), lost all contact with Earth shortly after landfall.<br/> <br/> You are Captain Zelnick, a human that was born on Unzervalt and who possesses a remarkable knack for Precursor technology. You were the one who worked out how to activate the Precursor installation.<br/> <br/> It was a factory for building starships. However, Unzervalt is mineral-poor, and there were not enough materials available to construct a complete vessel. Your task is to command this craft, the Vindicator, and return to Earth to tell them of the abandoned colony. Also, if the War with the Ur-Quan continues, you must fight for Earth and the Alliance as best you can.<br/> <br/> The default key mappings:<br/> <br/> In the menu: <br/> A, Start: Select<br/> B, Select: Back<br/> Y: Delete<br/> X: Backspace<br/> Select: Skip cutscene<br/> D-Pad: Move or type<br/> <br/> Navigation:<br/> Select: Menu<br/> D-Pad: Move<br/> <br/> Lander:<br/> A: Weapon<br/> B: Depart<br/> D-Pad: Move<br/> <br/> On the starmap:<br/> L/R: Zoom<br/> Y: Search<br/> <br/> Battle:<br/> A: Primary Attack<br/> B: Secondary Attack<br/> Select: Escape<br/> <br/> Text Input:<br/> D-Pad Up/Down: Select character<br/> D-Pad Left/Right: Move Cursor<br/> A: Confirm Input<br/> B: Cancel Input<br/> Shoulder Keys: Switch Upper/Lower Case.<br/> <br/> This port was possible, since the games source code is available under the GNU General Public License (http://www.gnu.org/copyleft/gpl.html), and this port is released under the same license conditions as well.<br/> In accordance with the GPL, the complete source code of the game with all modifications which were done in order to adapt it for the GCW Zero is included in the .opk file (sourcecode.tar.gz). The keyboard mappings are not part of the source code, but are defined within the uqm-0.7.0-content.uqm file, which is part of the game content. <br/> <br/> The game content is released under Creative Commons Attribution-Noncommercial-ShareAlike 2.5 (https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/2.5/). The original files can be found at http://sc2.sf.net/ and the only difference of the files in this OPK are the keybindings. Of course the same license applies.<br/> <br/> The list of people involved in the creation of the game is available at http://sc2.sourceforge.net/team.php.<br/> <br/> Installation of Addons:<br/> The official addons (voices, 3DO music and remixes) can simply be put in the ~/.uqm/addons folder (if the folder doesn't exist, feel free to create it) and enabled/disabled in the game settings menu.<br/> <br/> For unofficial addons a little manual work is required. These need to be unpacked in the ~/.uqm/useraddons folder (so that their .rmp files are directly in the useraddons folder, not a subfolder of it), and the paths in the .rmp files have to be edited to point to "useraddons" instead of the addon name.</description>
  </game>
  <game>
    <name>FBA 0.2.97.35</name>
    <short>Arcade machines emulator</short>
    <icon>emulator_128.png</icon>
    <link>fba.opk</link>
    <preview>0_9d420_ed745804_L.png</preview>
    <date>Wednesday, 11 Mar 2015</date>
    <author>Team FB Alpha</author>
    <portauthor>Dmitry Smagin</portauthor>
    <homepage>https://github.com/dmitrysmagin/fba-sdl</homepage>
    <description>FB Alpha is an arcade emulator supporting many hardware platforms like CPS1, CPS2, NEO-GEO, PGM, Cave and many others. Romset is compatible with Mame 0.159</description>
  </game>
  <game>
    <name>FreeBlocks</name>
    <short>A puzzle game similar to Tetris Attack.</short>
    <icon>game_128.png</icon>
    <link>freeblocks.opk</link>
    <preview>freeblocks.png</preview>
    <date>Tuesday, 10 Mar 2015</date>
    <author>Justin "dorkster" Jacobs</author>
    <portauthor>congusbongus</portauthor>
    <homepage>https://github.com/dorkster/freeblocks</homepage>
    <description>FreeBlocks is a puzzle game similar to Tetris Attack. Line up the blocks by color and attempt to reach the highest score!</description>
  </game>
  <game>
    <name>Nanobounce</name>
    <short>A frustrating bouncing-ball game.</short>
    <icon>game_128.png</icon>
    <link>nanobounce-04b-gcw0-free.opk</link>
    <preview>nanobounce.png</preview>
    <date>Saturday, 07 Mar 2015</date>
    <author>Carl Reinke (Mindless)</author>
    <portauthor/>
    <homepage>http://www.intoorbit.org/projects/nanobounce/</homepage>
    <description>The goal of the game is simple: bounce the ball to the exit.<br/> The exit is marked with green circles; exiting anywhere else will result in doom for the ball.<br/> The ball can jump off walls if it is pushed in the opposite direction as it hits the wall.<br/> <br/> The rest is simple enough.</description>
  </game>
  <game>
    <name>glutexto</name>
    <short>A very simple text editor.</short>
    <icon>application_128.png</icon>
    <link>glutexto.opk</link>
    <preview>glutexto.png</preview>
    <date>Sunday, 08 Feb 2015</date>
    <author>Ziz</author>
    <portauthor/>
    <homepage>https://github.com/theZiz/glutexto</homepage>
    <description>Glutexto is a simple text editor that allows you to create and modify text files on your GCW Zero such as configuration files.</description>
  </game>
  <game>
    <name>Triple Trapled</name>
    <short>Game about stacking blocks</short>
    <icon>game_128.png</icon>
    <link>tripleTrapled_v0.9.opk</link>
    <preview>tt.png</preview>
    <date>Wednesday, 31 Dec 2014</date>
    <author>Artur "zear" Rojek</author>
    <portauthor/>
    <homepage>https://github.com/zear/TripleTrapled</homepage>
    <description>Triple Trapled is a remake of "Triple Traple" by ABA Games.<br/> <br/> Instructions:<br/> -------------<br/> * Connect 3 blocks of the same color to break the chain.<br/> * Multiply your score by the number of additional blocks destroyed with the chain.<br/> * Use the blinking block to remove a single block of any color.<br/> * Every 5 seconds the game speed increases.<br/> * Game ends when the number of stacked blocks on the level reaches 50.<br/> <br/> Copyright:<br/> ----------<br/> * Author: Artur Rojek (zear)<br/> * License: MIT (see LICENSE.txt)<br/> <br/> Special thanks:<br/> * Kenta Cho - original game idea<br/> * Nebuleon - game testing<br/> * Senquack - game testing<br/> <br/> Changelog:<br/> ----------<br/> 2014/12/31, v0.9<br/> * initial game release</description>
  </game>
  <game>
    <name>OhBoy</name>
    <short>Gameboy/GBC emulator.</short>
    <icon>emulator_128.png</icon>
    <link>Ohboy_20141226.opk</link>
    <preview>screenshot069.png</preview>
    <date>Friday, 26 Dec 2014</date>
    <author>Ubyte, Fishybawb, Clach04</author>
    <portauthor>Hi-Ban</portauthor>
    <homepage>https://github.com/hi-ban/ohboy</homepage>
    <description>OhBoy is a port of the gnuboy Gameboy emulator with a basic menu system.<br/> <br/> Ohboy features include support for savestates, loading zipped roms, palette files, border images, different scalers and more.<br/> <br/> More info can be found here: <a href="http://boards.dingoonity.org/gcw-releases/ohboy/">Dingoonity forums</a></description>
  </game>
  <game>
    <name>Giana's Return</name>
    <short>Unofficial sequel of "The Great Giana Sisters"</short>
    <icon>game_128.png</icon>
    <link>gianas-return_v1.10.opk</link>
    <preview>giana.png</preview>
    <date>Wednesday, 24 Dec 2014</date>
    <author>Retroguru</author>
    <portauthor>Artur "zear" Rojek</portauthor>
    <homepage>http://www.gianas-return.de/</homepage>
    <description>Giana's Return aims to be a worthy unofficial sequel of "The Great Giana Sisters" - an alltime classic Jump'N'Run game made in the late eighties mainly by Armin Gessert, Manfred Trenz and Chris Hülsbeck, which gained massive attention as "Super Mario" copy, but still had its very own charm and fan base.<br/> <br/> Story:<br/> Evil Swampy and his followers have stolen the magic ruby, which made it once possible for Giana and Maria to return from their dream. Many creatures are after this ruby, but does it really have power, or was it just a coincidence?<br/> As this is not bad enough, Swampy fell in love at first sight with Giana's sister Maria and shamelessly kidnapped her. She simply has been at the wrong place at the wrong time.<br/> You take over the role of Giana, get back the magic ruby and most important of all, save your beloved sister Maria and get home save! Good Luck!<br/> <br/> Legal:<br/> Giana's Return is 100% FREEWARE and does not cost you a single cent, should you have paid for it please let us know so we can take legal steps and help others to avoid a possible trap. You are not allowed to distribute the download on any medias or online places without written permission. Official mirrors are available and listed on the official homepage - Please respect this! Contact information is available at it's official page!<br/> <br/> "The Great Giana Sisters" is a registered trademark. The Team behind this game does not intend to break any copyright, but to bring a high quality fan sequel free of charge to all Giana fans out there. Permission has been granted from the actual owners.<br/> <br/> No one of the original team was involved in the creation of this game, besides Armin and Manfred giving feedback on (for now) pretty old betas.</description>
  </game>
  <game>
    <name>SDL Sand</name>
    <short>Falling sand simulation</short>
    <icon>game_128.png</icon>
    <link>sdlsand.opk</link>
    <preview>sdlsand.png</preview>
    <date>Saturday, 06 Dec 2014</date>
    <author>Thomas René Sidor, Kristian Jensen</author>
    <portauthor>Artur "zear" Rojek</portauthor>
    <homepage>https://github.com/zear/SDLSand</homepage>
    <description>The aim of this program is to simulate different particles (such as sand, water, oil or fire) interacting with each other.<br/> Freedom is given to the player to experiment with the different materials in a sandbox environment.<br/> <br/> Keymap<br/> -----------------<br/> SELECT: Exit game<br/> START: Clear screen<br/> Joystick: Move cursor<br/> D-PAD left/right: change brush type<br/> D-PAD up/down: decrease/increase pen size<br/> A: paint w/ selected brush type<br/> B: limit cursor speed to 1px/frame<br/> Y: set the brush type to eraser<br/> X: turn on/off emitters (applies to screen top only)<br/> L/R: decrease/increase emitters density (applies to screen top only)<br/> <br/> Usage<br/> ----------------<br/> Select a brush type from the panel on the bottom part of the screen and draw while pressing<br/> the A button. Use the B button to perform more accurate cursor movements. The particles falling from the top of the screen can be disabled at any moment by pressing the X button, or decreased/increased with L/R shoulder buttons.<br/> <br/> Brush types (from left to right):<br/> <br/> Group 1 (particles):<br/> * water<br/> * sand<br/> * salt<br/> * oil<br/> * fire<br/> * acid<br/> * dirt<br/> <br/> Group 2 (emitters):<br/> * water spout<br/> * sand spout<br/> * salt spout<br/> * oil spout<br/> <br/> Group 3 (solids):<br/> * wall<br/> * torch<br/> * stove<br/> * plant<br/> * ice<br/> * iron wall<br/> * void<br/> <br/> Group 4:<br/> * eraser<br/> <br/> The authors<br/> ----------------<br/> Thomas René Sidor (Studying computer science at the university of Copenhagen, Denmark) (Personal homepage: http://www.mcbyte.dk)<br/> Kristian Jensen (Studying computer science at Roskilde University, Denmark)<br/> Artur Rojek - GCW Zero port<br/> <br/> Acknowledgements<br/> ----------------<br/> CCmdLine - command line parser by Chris Losinger (http://www.codeproject.com/cpp/ccmdline.asp)<br/> SDL - Simple DirectMedia Library (http://www.libsdl.org)<br/> <br/> Origins<br/> -----------------<br/> The SDL Sand game (The Falling SDL-Sand Game) is a C++ implementation of the original 'World of<br/> Sand' (and later 'Hell of Sand') game implemented in JAVA. SDL Sand uses the SDL (Simple DirectMedia<br/> Library - http://www.libsdl.org/) library for screen output. Therefore the implementation can<br/> possibly run on every platform supported by SDL.<br/> <br/> The aim is to create a faster implementation of the game and possibly extend its features.<br/> <br/> Links<br/> -----------------<br/> Project link: http://sourceforge.net/projects/sdlsand<br/> The originial World of Sand from DOFI-BLOG (http://ishi.blog2.fc2.com/blog-entry-158.html)<br/> The later version - Hell of Sand from DOFI-BLOG (http://ishi.blog2.fc2.com/blog-entry-164.html)<br/> A Falling Sand Game forum (http://www.fallingsandgame.com/)<br/> Falling Sand Game hosted (http://chir.ag/stuff/sand/)<br/> <br/> License<br/> -----------------<br/> SDL Sand is released under GPLv2 license. See included LICENSE file for details.</description>
  </game>
  <game>
    <name>Seahorse Adventures</name>
    <short>You're a seahorse, and you want to go to the Moon!</short>
    <icon>game_128.png</icon>
    <link>barbiesa-1.1.5.opk</link>
    <preview>barbiesa-1-1.png</preview>
    <date>Saturday, 06 Dec 2014</date>
    <author>The Olde Battleaxe (philhassey, pekuja, tim, drpetter, trick)</author>
    <portauthor>Nebuleon</portauthor>
    <homepage>https://github.com/Nebuleon/barbie-seahorse-adventures</homepage>
    <description>A fun little platformer made by The Olde Battleaxe for <a href="https://www.pyweek.org/4/">PyWeek 4</a>. (<a href="http://www.imitationpickles.org/barbie/">Original site</a>. This port is based on the version 1.1 Deluxe.)<br/> <br/> You're a seahorse, and you have to go to the Moon! There are enemies in your way, which you must defeat, and landscapes that will end up confusing you...<br/> <br/> You shoot bubbles from your... face... and those bubbles destroy enemies and turn them into bubbles, which you can ride to raise yourself to new heights. Three bubbles from your face are enough to defeat most enemies, or one if you have hair, but there is one thing that your bubbles cannot defeat alone...<br/> <br/> Controls are explained in-game (see Help).<br/> <br/> GPLv2 license.</description>
  </game>
  <game>
    <name>Neverball / Neverputt</name>
    <short>A pair of addictive physics-based 3D games.</short>
    <icon>game_128.png</icon>
    <link>neverball.opk</link>
    <preview>screenshot031.png</preview>
    <date>Wednesday, 03 Dec 2014</date>
    <author>Robert Kooima</author>
    <portauthor>Daniel 'senquack' Silsby</portauthor>
    <homepage>https://github.com/senquack/neverball</homepage>
    <description>Tilt the floor to roll a ball through an obstacle course before time runs out. Neverball is part puzzle game, part action game, and entirely a test of skill. It is similar to the Gamecube/iPhone game 'Super Monkey Ball'. It is GPU-accelerated and fully supports the GCW Zero's tilt G-Sensor.<br/> <br/> Neverball is also two games in one: it includes Neverputt, a miniature golf game with many unique levels, built on the physics and graphics engine of Neverball.<br/> <br/>
                <ul class="gallery2" style="width: 660px;">
                        <li><img src="http://gcw-zero.com/images/articles/neverball_01.png"/></li>
                        <li><img src="http://gcw-zero.com/images/articles/neverball_02.png"/></li>
                        <li class="description"><p>Screenshots: Neverball</p></li>
                        <li><img src="http://gcw-zero.com/images/articles/neverputt_01.png"/></li>
                        <li><img src="http://gcw-zero.com/images/articles/neverputt_02.png"/></li>
                        <li class="description"><p>Screenshots: Neverputt</p></li>
                </ul><br/> <a href="http://boards.dingoonity.org/gcw-releases/neverball-and-neverputt-for-gcw-zero/">Official forum release thread for comments, requests, and issues.</a><br/>
                <a href="http://neverball.org">Original game's website</a><br/> <br/> -------------------------------------------------<br/> PORT FEATURES: <br/> -------------------------------------------------<br/> * Support for G-Sensor tilt control<br/> * Many new controls settings added<br/> * 'Finesse Mode' enables finer movement control<br/> * Camera rotation acceleration<br/> * In addition to all the official v1.6.0 levelsets, it includes three excellent levelsets from community map-creator Reshaun Francis<br/> -------------------------------------------------<br/> CONTROLS:<br/> -------------------------------------------------<br/> Neverball:<br/> Move: DPAD / Analog-stick / G-Sensor / ABXY<br/> Toggle 'Finesse Mode': Select + L Trigger<br/> Change camera mode: Select + R Trigger<br/> Rotate camera: L / R Triggers<br/> In-game menu: Start Button<br/> Toggle G-Sensor On/Off: Hold Select for 2 seconds<br/> <br/> * NOTE: Finesse mode does not affect movement with A/B/X/Y buttons, and this is intentional.<br/> <br/> Neverputt:<br/> Aim: DPAD or Triggers (fast rotate)<br/> Aim faster: X / Y buttons<br/> Putt: A / B buttons<br/> In-game menu: Start button<br/> <br/> -------------------------------------------------<br/> INSTALLING ADDITIONAL LEVEL SETS:<br/> -------------------------------------------------<br/> Use FTP to copy the .ZIP level pack file to your /home/.neverball/ folder. Be sure your FTP client is set to treat files as BINARY and that any option to show hidden folders is ON. In FileZilla, go to Menu-&gt;Server-&gt;"Force showing hidden files".<br/> <br/> -------------------------------------------------<br/> INSTALLING ADDITIONAL LEVEL SETS:<br/> -------------------------------------------------<br/> v1.1: Second GCW release December 4th 2014<br/> * Fixed joystick handling bug in original Neverputt code that prevented going back to title screen when final scores were displayed<br/> <br/> v1.0: Initial GCW release</description>
  </game>
  <game>
    <name>UAE4ALL</name>
    <short>Amiga 500 emulator</short>
    <icon>emulator_128.png</icon>
    <link>uae4all.opk</link>
    <preview>uae4all.png</preview>
    <date>Tuesday, 02 Dec 2014</date>
    <author>UAE team, Chui</author>
    <portauthor>Nebuleon, Artur "zear" Rojek</portauthor>
    <homepage>https://github.com/zear/uae4all</homepage>
    <description>UAE4ALL is an Amiga 500 emulator based on UAE 0.8.22 core.<br/> Version: GCW Zero Release 1.<br/> <br/> List of authors and contributors:<br/> * UAE authors (see ./docs/CREDITS)<br/> * Chui - original UAE4ALL author<br/> * Nebuleon &amp; Zear - GCW Zero port and improvements<br/> * Hi-Ban - new UAE4ALL logo and minor graphical changes (Hi-Ban's contributions licensed under Creative Commons Attribution-ShareAlike 4.0 International)<br/> <br/> Important note:<br/> This version of the program is a *port* of the original emulator.<br/> The authors of this port are NOT maintaining the emulation core.<br/> For any issues related to the emulation performance, please contact the *original* UAE/UAE4ALL authors.<br/> <br/> Before first use:<br/> Provide a valid Amiga 500 Kickstart bootstrap firmware and copy it to the following location:<br/> (FTP)/home/.uae4all/kick.rom<br/> UAE4ALL will refuse to launch without this file present.<br/> <br/> Launching programs:<br/> UAE4ALL will work with disk images in "adf" and "adz" format.<br/> 1) Copy appropriate files to a location of your choice in the GCW Zero filesystem<br/> 2) Launch UAE4ALL emulator<br/> 3) Select "Load disk image" option<br/> 4) Choose "Load DF0 image" (Floppy Drive #1) or "Load DF1 image" (Floppy Drive #2) to load a disk image to the appropriate drive.<br/> NOTE: Bootable disks need to be loaded to DF0.<br/> 5) Point the file selector to a directory location with the disk images and select the image you want to load.<br/> NOTE: This directory location will be stored as a default directory for future UAE4ALL runs.<br/> 6) For bootable images, select "Start Amiga" or "Reset Amiga" to boot a new image. For non-bootable images, select "Return to Amiga" and follow instructions of the currently emulated program.<br/> Adjusting the frame rate:<br/> Setting the frameskip value to "auto" will limit the emulated program speed to 50 frames per second. Use this option for programs meant to be run on PAL Amiga machines. Most Amiga programs were designed for this frame rate.<br/> Setting the frameskip value to "0" will limit the emulated program speed to 60 frames per second. Use this option for programs meant to be run on NTSC Amiga machines.<br/> <br/> Controls (during emulation):<br/> D-PAD/analog joystick - control amiga joystick (if mouse emulation turned off) / amiga mouse (if mouse emulation turned on)<br/> A - joystick button #1<br/> B - joystick button #2<br/> Y - mouse button #1<br/> X - mouse button #2<br/> L - enable/disable mouse emulation<br/> R - enable/disable on-screen-keyboard<br/> START - super throttle<br/> SELECT - emulator menu</description>
  </game>
  <game>
    <name>Worship Vector</name>
    <short>Tower Defense game with simplistic graphics.</short>
    <icon>game_128.png</icon>
    <link>wvector.opk</link>
    <preview>wv.png</preview>
    <date>Thursday, 27 Nov 2014</date>
    <author>Quasist</author>
    <portauthor>Johnny On Flame</portauthor>
    <homepage>https://github.com/JohnnyonFlame/Worship-Vector</homepage>
    <description>In this wire-frame stylized game your task is to construct various kinds of shooting towers in order to protect your base against the waves of geometric-shaped enemies. Don't let too many of them reach it, otherwise it's a game over!<br/> <br/> Choose wisely from the 5 varieties of the towers: Minigun, Anti-air, Artillery, Slowray and Sniper. Each has a different effect on the incoming foes, diverging in the fire-power, reload rate and the construction cost.<br/> <br/> Construct the Plants to increase the money flow.</description>
  </game>
  <game>
    <name>Enigma</name>
    <short>To say that Enigma is a puzzle game is an understatement.</short>
    <icon>game_128.png</icon>
    <link>enigma.opk</link>
    <preview>screenshot003.png</preview>
    <date>Monday, 17 Nov 2014</date>
    <author>Enigma Team</author>
    <portauthor>senquack (Dan Silsby)</portauthor>
    <homepage>https://github.com/senquack/Enigma-for-GCWZero</homepage>
    <description>Inspired by the classic game Onyx, Enigma is really a huge collection of puzzle games, and each of its 550 unique levels challenge the intelligence, dexterity and sheer willpower of its players anew. Enigma is simple to learn, challenging to play, but hard to master. Players of almost any age can enjoy it. It contains hundreds of levels. And if that isn't enough, it's also completely free. If you like puzzle games and have a steady hand, Enigma will probably keep you busy for hours on end.<br/> <br/> -------------------------------------------------<br/> IMPORTANT NOTE :<br/> -------------------------------------------------<br/> Because of copyright laws, Enigma for the GCW Zero does not include the five official level-packs based on the original Oxyd game. Installing them yourself is easy, however. Run the game once so that it creates a folder in your home directory:<br/> $HOME/.enigma/ (Using FTP, this will be /home/.enigma/)<br/> <br/> Download the latest Windows .ZIP binary release from here: <a href="http://www.nongnu.org/enigma/download.html">Enigma downloads page</a><br/> <br/> Extract it to a folder on your computer and, using FTP, copy the following five folders into your GCW Zero's /home/.enigma/levels folder:<br/> <br/> data/levels/enigma_esprit/<br/> data/levels/enigma_oxyd/<br/> data/levels/enigma_oxydextra/<br/> data/levels/enigma_oxydmagnum/<br/> data/levels/enigma_peroxyd/<br/> <br/> NOTE: if using FTP, you want to be sure you have any option to show hidden folders turned ON, or else you won't be able to see the /home/.enigma/ folder. Also, make sure BINARY TRANSFER MODE is turned on.<br/> <br/> Your $HOME/.enigma/levels/ folder should now look something like this:<br/> auto/<br/> cross/<br/> enigma_esprit/<br/> enigma_oxyd/<br/> enigma_oxydextra/<br/> enigma_oxydmagnum/<br/> enigma_peroxyd/<br/> externaldata/<br/> legacy_dat/<br/> <br/> Now, start up Enigma and you will now see the Oxyd levels under the "Deja-Vu" level-pack category.<br/> <br/> BTW, if you ever create or download any additional levels, they should go into the auto/ folder shown above.<br/> <br/> -------------------------------------------------<br/> PLAYING THE ORIGINAL OXYD LEVELS:<br/> -------------------------------------------------<br/> Enigma is able to read the original Oxyd family of games' data files! If you own the original games, you can copy the .DAT level files into your $HOME/.enigma/levels/legacy_dat/ folder. The level sets will then show up in the "Dongleware" category.<br/> <br/> -------------------------------------------------<br/> MORE ABOUT THE GAME:<br/> -------------------------------------------------<br/> The object of the game is to find and uncover pairs of identically colored 'Oxyd' stones. Simple? Yes. Easy? Certainly not! Hidden traps, vast mazes, laser beams, and most of all, countless hairy puzzles usually block your direct way to the Oxyd stones. Enigma's game objects (and there are hundreds of them, lest you get bored) interact in many unexpected ways, and since many of them follow the laws of physics (Enigma's special laws of physics, that is), controlling them isn't always trivial ...<br/> <br/> The original goal of the Enigma project was to keep the spirit of the Oxyd game series alive, after its publisher decided to leave the gaming business in 2002. Fans of this famous game will experience deja-vu. However, over the years, Enigma has absorbed ideas from countless other popular games, and added its own unique twists to each of them.<br/> <br/> To learn fully how to play the game, you are encouraged to read the excellent <a href="http://www.nongnu.org/enigma/manual_1.20/manual/enigma.html">official user's manual</a> and also visit the <a href="http://www.nongnu.org/enigma/">official Enigma home page</a><br/> <br/> -------------------------------------------------<br/> PORT FEATURES: <br/> -------------------------------------------------<br/> The original game is meant to be played with a mouse. Because of this, I have taken pains to make it as playable as possible on our handheld gaming system that lacks a mouse. The marble can be controlled with either the Analog Stick, the DPAD, or the internal G-sensor. In order to play with the G-sensor you must first enable it in the game's settings. Playing using the DPAD would be a bit like cheating, and I discourage you from doing so. <br/> <br/> In addition to the default movement speed, you can move with three additional speeds: Speed #1 is mapped to the B button, Speed #2 to the X button, and Speed #3 to the Y button. You may change these speeds in the options menu, under "Controls", along with a few other options, like enabling or calibrating the G-sensor, or changing deadzones.<br/> <br/> -------------------------------------------------<br/> CONTROLS:<br/> -------------------------------------------------<br/> There is a handy in-game list of the control mappings. Select "Help" from the main menu and then select "GCW Zero Controls".</description>
  </game>
  <game>
    <name>Finite</name>
    <short>Word game</short>
    <icon>game_128.png</icon>
    <link>finite.opk</link>
    <preview>finite.png</preview>
    <date>Saturday, 15 Nov 2014</date>
    <author>Joe Vargas (jxv)</author>
    <portauthor/>
    <homepage>https://github.com/jxv/finite</homepage>
    <description>How clever of a speller are you? Play Finite to find out. Compete with your friends or an AI.</description>
  </game>
  <game>
    <name>rRootage</name>
    <short>GPU-accelerated 'bullet-hell' shoot-em-up game</short>
    <icon>game_128.png</icon>
    <link>rrootage.opk</link>
    <preview>rrootage.png</preview>
    <date>Sunday, 09 Nov 2014</date>
    <author>Kenta Cho</author>
    <portauthor>Daniel Silsby (senquack)</portauthor>
    <homepage>https://github.com/senquack/rRootage-for-Handhelds</homepage>
    <description>rRootage is a popular 'SHMUP' originally released as freeware by Japanese programmer Kenta Cho in 2003. You must avoid bullet barrages and use your laser to destroy the enemy battleship. The closer you are, the more damage you cause. You get a new ship after 200,000 points and then every 500,000 points.<br/> <br/> My GCW port is a highly-optimized OpenGLES conversion that runs at 100% full speed. It also features several new options the original game lacked:<br/> * Optionally rotated-and-zoomed playfield<br/> * Completely customizable control scheme<br/> * Trainer "cheat" modes (high-score saving is disabled when in use)<br/> * Laser can be turned on by default<br/> * Music and "bullet-time slowdown" can easily be disabled<br/> * Bullet-shape outlines can be turned on or off (good for 320x240 resolutions)<br/> <br/> -------------------------------------------------<br/> MODES OF PLAY:<br/> -------------------------------------------------<br/> 1.) NORMAL MODE - This is the standard game mode. Your ship is slower when firing the laser. You have a limited number of bombs that clear enemy bullets.<br/> <br/> 2.) PSY MODE - This mode is inspired by the "Psyvariar" family of games. When your ship grazes a bullet, the gauge fills up. When the gauge is full, your ship becomes temporarily invincible. Use this short period of time to graze as many bullets as possible and become invincible again... This technique is also called 'scratching'. The 'special' attack is used to "scratch" on a wider area, but it slows down your movement. <br/> <br/> 3.) IKA MODE - This mode is inspired by the legendary game "Ikaruga" for Dreamcast … Gamecube. Your ship can switch between red and blue colors. Your ship absorbs bullets of the same color but others destroy it. Absorbed bullets are automatically changed into lasers that damage the enemy. <br/> <br/> 4.) GW MODE - This mode is inspired by the "Gigawing" family of games. Your ship can reflect all bullets around it. This is achieved by keeping the 'special' button pressed until the gauge becomes empty. The reflector can only be engaged when its gauge is full. You must wait for the "OK" mark.</description>
  </game>
  <game>
    <name>Slappa!</name>
    <short>Arcade kungfu minigame</short>
    <icon>game_128.png</icon>
    <link>slappa.opk</link>
    <preview>slappa.png</preview>
    <date>Sunday, 26 Oct 2014</date>
    <author>cxong</author>
    <portauthor/>
    <homepage>https://github.com/cxong/Slappa</homepage>
    <description>Arcade kung fu minigame made in pygame, for PyWeek: https://pyweek.org/e/Slappa/</description>
  </game>
  <game>
    <name>WetSpot 2</name>
    <short>Action puzzle game similar to Pengo.</short>
    <icon>game_128.png</icon>
    <link>wetspot2.opk</link>
    <preview>shot0022.gif</preview>
    <date>Friday, 24 Oct 2014</date>
    <author>Angelo Mottola (coding, gfx), Drozerix (music)</author>
    <portauthor>Dmitry Smagin</portauthor>
    <homepage>https://github.com/dmitrysmagin/wetspot2</homepage>
    <description>In this game you control a small crab and your target is to kill every monster on the current level. Since you have no weapons, you must push bricks that form the walls of the level. When the brick hits some obstacle it releases a bonus. Not every wall is movable so beware!</description>
  </game>
  <game>
    <name>Koules</name>
    <short>A wacky physics-based arcade game... in space</short>
    <icon>game_128.png</icon>
    <link>koules.opk</link>
    <preview>koules_screenshot.png</preview>
    <date>Saturday, 04 Oct 2014</date>
    <author>Jan Hubicka</author>
    <portauthor>Daniel Silsby (senquack)</portauthor>
    <homepage>https://github.com/senquack/Koules-for-Handhelds</homepage>
    <description>Koules is a fun … silly physics-based homebrew game released in 1995 by Jan Hubicka for Linux. It is one of the first arcade-style games ever released for Linux and I've always liked playing it. So, I decided to bring it to the handheld masses.<br/> <br/> You are the big yellow ball with eyes. You must knock out the other balls that come towards you (Evil Koules fighters). Small blue balls give you extra mass, while small green balls give you extra acceleration. Yellow balls give you tons of both. White balls steal all your power-ups. Gold balls allow you to steal power-ups from other balls. There are 99 levels and as you progress, the game introduces new elements and gets quite a bit harder. I suggest playing on the "HARD" difficulty for maximum fun, once you pick up the basics.<br/> <br/> Don't worry, the game will explain the new elements to you as you move along.<br/> <br/> ----------------------------------------------------<br/> CHANGE LOG: <br/> ----------------------------------------------------<br/> v1.0: First release (GCW version):<br/> * Adapted from my previous GP2X/Wiz ports:<br/> * Added g-sensor/analog stick support<br/> * Two-player-on-one-device support<br/> * Added music by DST @ nosoapradio.us (Creative Commons 3.0 License)<br/> * Added cool randomly-generated plasma background<br/> * Adjusted volume of two sound samples that were too loud<br/> * Fixed major bug in original game regarding fread()/fwrite() of rc files.<br/> * Made HARD difficulty mode the default mode.. MEDIUM difficulty is too slow and easy.<br/> * Adjusted NIGHTMARE difficulty mode to actually be playable.<br/> * Adjusted HARD difficulty mode so that your player has a bit less mass (hard was also too easy).<br/> * Fixed various bugs, especially in menu.c<br/> <br/> Pre-v1.0: Initial SVGALIB-&gt;SDL conversion also by Dan Silsby (senquack)<br/> <br/> ----------------------------------------------------<br/> TIPS:<br/> ----------------------------------------------------<br/> Instead of charging at everything you see, try to trick enemies into chasing you and dodge them at the last second. You can get them to crash into walls and the red/green holes that appear. Use the green "magnetic holes" for moving in a slingshot effect.<br/> <br/> ----------------------------------------------------<br/> CONTROLS … TWO-PLAYER MODE:<br/> ----------------------------------------------------<br/> START: Pause<br/> SELECT: Exit to main menu<br/> L+R TRIGGERS: Re-calibrate g-sensor<br/> <br/> In one-player mode: you move with either the D-PAD or the A/B/X/Y buttons, your pick. G-sensor and analog stick control can be enabled from the main menu. If the g-sensor fails to work, that is a bug in the firmware currently being worked on. If you power-off your unit and hold the reset button for 30+ seconds that should get the g-sensor working again.<br/> <br/> In two-player mode: two people play on one device, either deathmatch or cooperatively. Player 1 uses the DPAD and Player 2 uses either the A/B/X/Y buttons (GCW held horizontally) or the analog stick (GCW held vertically).</description>
  </game>
  <game>
    <name>Liero</name>
    <short>An old-school earthworm action game</short>
    <icon>game_128.png</icon>
    <link>liero.opk</link>
    <preview>liero.png</preview>
    <date>Friday, 03 Oct 2014</date>
    <author>Joosa Riekkinen, Erik Lindroos and others</author>
    <portauthor>Artur "zear" Rojek</portauthor>
    <homepage>https://github.com/gcwnow/liero</homepage>
    <description>Liero is a simple game. Pick your five weapons, and unleash your inner fury. The game is always played one versus one on a map of your choice.<br/> <br/> To shoot is of course easy enough to figure out, but if you want to step up your game, you need to figure out things like how to swing yourself to safety with the ninja rope, to use timed weapons for area denial, to hunt without being hunted, to ambush, hit and run, and control that darn guided missile.<br/> <br/> If you can do all these things, you may one day become a true champion, as the players in this video attempt.</description>
  </game>
  <game>
    <name>ReGBA 1.45.5</name>
    <short>GBA emulator for the GCW Zero</short>
    <icon>emulator_128.png</icon>
    <link>regba-1.45.5.opk</link>
    <preview>ReGBA GEMini no scaling.png</preview>
    <date>Thursday, 28 Aug 2014</date>
    <author>Exophase, Gradius, Takka, Normmatt, Nebuleon, others</author>
    <portauthor>Nebuleon, JohnnyonFlame, pcercuei</portauthor>
    <homepage>https://github.com/Nebuleon/ReGBA</homepage>
    <description>ReGBA is a GBA emulator for the GCW Zero. It is ultimately based on gpSP for the Playstation Portable by Exophase and contains improvements made over the years by Takka and Nebuleon.<br/> <br/> It features audio with under 60 ms latency, optional full-screen scaling, remappable controls on the GCW Zero buttons (but no joystick support yet), an open-source and freely redistributable GBA BIOS replacement by Normmatt, SRAM saving, saved states and fast-forwarding. All settings can be overridden per game.<br/> <br/> The focus of this emulator is on performance. As such, its compatibility may not be perfect. It does, however, run many popular commercial games and homebrew titles.<br/> <br/> <b>Unified menu</b> means that this emulator's menu can be entered with Start+Select or by flicking the Power switch upwards without pressing other buttons.<br/> <br/> Source code and bug reports: <a href="https://github.com/Nebuleon/ReGBA">https://github.com/Nebuleon/ReGBA</a><br/> Manual: <a href="http://wiki.gcw-zero.com/ReGBA">http://wiki.gcw-zero.com/ReGBA</a> (also available for reading on the GCW Zero)</description>
  </game>
  <game>
    <name>PocketSNES 2014-08-24</name>
    <short>Super Nintendo emulator based on Snes9x 1.43</short>
    <icon>emulator_128.png</icon>
    <link>PocketSNES-20140824-1.opk</link>
    <preview>pocketsnes-hiban-menu.png</preview>
    <date>Thursday, 28 Aug 2014</date>
    <author>Snes9x team (anomie, zones, Nach, byuu, Mkendora, etc.)</author>
    <portauthor>Paul Cercueil, Nebuleon, hi-ban</portauthor>
    <homepage>https://github.com/Nebuleon/PocketSNES</homepage>
    <description>IMPORTANT: This version is unable to read PocketSNES August 2013 (Snes9x 1.39)'s saved states, but can read its SRAM (.srm) files. If you have older saved states, you can use <a href="http://www.gcw-zero.com/PocketSNES.opk">the older version of PocketSNES</a> or, before installing this version, load the saved states in PocketSNES August 2013 and let the game save its SRAM.<br/> <br/> PocketSNES is a Super Nintendo/Super Famicom emulator for the GCW Zero. It is ultimately based on Snes9x 1.43 and contains some minor core optimisations by Nebuleon.<br/> <br/> It features audio with under 60 ms latency, optional full-screen scaling with a fast scaler or an approximate bilinear scaler, SRAM saving and saved states. All settings can be overridden per game.<br/> <br/> <b>Unified menu</b> means that this emulator's menu can be entered with Start+Select or by flicking the Power switch upwards without pressing other buttons.<br/> <br/> You can read its manual at <a href="http://wiki.gcw-zero.com/PocketSNES">http://wiki.gcw-zero.com/PocketSNES</a> and on your GCW Zero.<br/> <br/> Source code is at <a href="https://github.com/Nebuleon/PocketSNES">https://github.com/Nebuleon/PocketSNES</a> under the Snes9x non-commercial use license.</description>
  </game>
  <game>
    <name>zerox86</name>
    <short>x86 emulator by Patrick Aalto</short>
    <icon>emulator_128.png</icon>
    <link>zerox86.opk</link>
    <preview>4DOS.png</preview>
    <date>Sunday, 27 Jul 2014</date>
    <author>Patrick Aalto</author>
    <portauthor>Patrick Aalto</portauthor>
    <homepage>http://zerox86.patrickaalto.com/</homepage>
    <description>zerox86 is a PC emulator for the Game Consoles Worldwide (GCW) Zero handheld game console. Its purpose is to allow you to run old DOS games on your GCW0. It is based on the DSx86 PC emulator for Nintendo DS game console.</description>
  </game>
  <game>
    <name>Xump</name>
    <short>The Final Run</short>
    <icon>game_128.png</icon>
    <link>xump_v.1.0-gcw-zero.opk</link>
    <preview>xump.png</preview>
    <date>Thursday, 03 Jul 2014</date>
    <author>Retroguru</author>
    <portauthor>Artur "zear" Rojek</portauthor>
    <homepage>http://retroguru.com/xump/</homepage>
    <description>Xump - The Final Run is a simple multi-platform puzzler by Retroguru. Initially released by Psilocybin Development in 2005 the game has been improved in almost every aspect you can imagine. New graphics, new levels, new music, new options, new everything...<br/> <br/> Help Holger to clean up deserted space fields. As this is a very dangerous task for a human being a headbot named Xump will be the one who has to suffer.<br/> <br/> Your main task is to clean all dissolveable tiles on several single-screen levels by simply stepping on them, one by one. Few fields are secured with mines and need a double tap. Mines can be blown up when passing by or deminded by Xump when staying on this specific field for a short moment. Certainly the mission sounds easier than it will be.</description>
  </game>
  <game>
    <name>Sqrxz</name>
    <short>Mindblasting frustration deluxe!</short>
    <icon>game_128.png</icon>
    <link>sqrxz-v.1.0b-gcw-zero.opk</link>
    <preview>sqrxz1.png</preview>
    <date>Friday, 20 Jun 2014</date>
    <author>Retroguru</author>
    <portauthor>Artur "zear" Rojek</portauthor>
    <homepage>http://retroguru.com/sqrxz/</homepage>
    <description>Sqrxz requires fast reflexes and is a simply mindblasting Jump’n’Run puzzle game with high frustration factor originally made in 1996 by Marcus Vesterlund (Maze) and John Holmvall (Hojo) for DOS and Windows 9x.<br/> <br/> Sqrxz (2010) is a remake of a game with the same name and has been created by Rodolphe Boixel (Thor), Shahzad Sahaib (Kojote), Simon Butler and Brendan Ratliff (Syphus). Minor support came from Marcus Vesterlund himself who also gave permission to redo his game. Denny Müller (Mulle) supported the team with a WordPress-Theme for the official page and Rabia Sahaib (Mahek) made three more levels.<br/> <br/> A remake should be usually bearing improvements, so does Sqrxz 2010. Beside the “classic” graphic mode, there is a new mode with “deluxe” graphics. The main gameplay was modified in a way that you need to collect all items to open the door at the end of each level, which makes some levels harder than they actually already were. Extended “fun” is guarantueed with additional three levels, unseen before. Each level does have it’s own chiptune and adds up to the retro feeling. A Top 10 highscore table will hold all your records. For the ones who like hidden features, there is even a small easter egg!</description>
  </game>
  <game>
    <name>Fceux 2.2.2</name>
    <short>NES/Famicom emulator</short>
    <icon>emulator_128.png</icon>
    <link>fceux.opk</link>
    <preview>cc8a94da-80f6-11e3-934d-1b6080f2c805.png</preview>
    <date>Sunday, 15 Jun 2014</date>
    <author>Fceux team</author>
    <portauthor>Dmitry Smagin</portauthor>
    <homepage>https://github.com/dmitrysmagin/fceu320-rzx50</homepage>
    <description>NES/Famicom emulator based on Fceux 2.2.2 with gui from well-known Fceu320.</description>
  </game>
  <game>
    <name>Spout</name>
    <short>A simple caveflying game.</short>
    <icon>game_128.png</icon>
    <link>spout.opk</link>
    <preview>spout.png</preview>
    <date>Tuesday, 20 May 2014</date>
    <author>Kuni</author>
    <portauthor>Alekmaul</portauthor>
    <homepage>https://github.com/alekmaul/spout</homepage>
    <description>In Spout, your goal is to guide your ship as high as possible through a vertical cave of sorts without crashing. The path is blocked though, and you must destroy the walls and ceiling to clear your way. Sounds easy, but there's a catch to the game, you don't have a gun to blast your way through - instead you must use the exhaust from your ship to erode away any surroundings that hinder your way, which can result in some tricky maneuvers. There is also time limited check points that adds a bit of urgency to the gameplay.<br/> <br/> The map is randomly generated so it's always a fresh challenge, and the game is great for a quick play because of the simple premise, and because it's just plain fun.</description>
  </game>
  <game>
    <name>Snowman</name>
    <short>A game about a snowman.</short>
    <icon>game_128.png</icon>
    <link>snowman.opk</link>
    <preview>snowman.png</preview>
    <date>Tuesday, 20 May 2014</date>
    <author>Ziz</author>
    <portauthor/>
    <homepage>https://github.com/theZiz/snowman</homepage>
    <description>Your goal is to finish all the levels. In order to finish a level, kill a given amount of enemies. Collect snow-coins to get bigger, because you will lose: <br/> * 3 snow-coins, if an enemy hits you,<br/> * 2 snow-coins, if you shoot,<br/> * 1 snow-coin, if you jump<br/> * all snow-coins of your big belly, if you use the ball attack<br/> <br/> If you lose all your snow-coins you die and have to restart the level. So economize your snow!<br/> <br/> If you find a broom, use it! You make double damage and don't lose the snow, but you need to be on a very close distance to your enemy.</description>
  </game>
  <game>
    <name>Puzzletube</name>
    <short>A puzzle game on a tube.</short>
    <icon>game_128.png</icon>
    <link>puzzletube.opk</link>
    <preview>puzzletube.png</preview>
    <date>Tuesday, 20 May 2014</date>
    <author>Ziz</author>
    <portauthor>Artur "zear" Rojek</portauthor>
    <homepage>https://github.com/theZiz/puzzletube</homepage>
    <description>Features:<br/> * 5 languages (English, German, Italian, Dutch, Norsk)<br/> * Genuine tube based puzzle game idea<br/> * 3 game modes with 2 difficulties<br/> * Fancy 3D graphics<br/> * Trophies<br/> * Great music from Nick May or custom background music<br/> * Cool sound effects (also from Nick)<br/> * Explosions. Explosions everywhere!<br/> * C4A support</description>
  </game>
  <game>
    <name>Sqrxz 4</name>
    <short>Cold Cash.</short>
    <icon>game_128.png</icon>
    <link>sqrxz4-v.1.00-gcw-zero.opk</link>
    <preview>sqrxz4.png</preview>
    <date>Thursday, 24 Apr 2014</date>
    <author>Retroguru</author>
    <portauthor>Artur "zear" Rojek</portauthor>
    <homepage>http://retroguru.com/sqrxz4/</homepage>
    <description>Many friends of hardcore action games demand it and we have listened to all voices. The fourth part of the (now) quadrilogy Jump'n Think series Sqrxz brings you onto a cold, icy island. Shiny marbles, evil penguins and ghosts, underwater creatures and much more to expect.</description>
  </game>
  <game>
    <name>Kobo Deluxe</name>
    <short>An addictive space shoot'em up</short>
    <icon>game_128.png</icon>
    <link>kobodl.opk</link>
    <preview>kobodx.png</preview>
    <date>Tuesday, 22 Apr 2014</date>
    <author>Akira Higuchi, Masanao Izumo, Simon Peter, Florian Schulze, Jeremy Sheeley, Erik Auerswald, David Olofson</author>
    <portauthor>Kuwanger</portauthor>
    <homepage>https://github.com/kuwanger/kobodl_gcw0</homepage>
    <description>Kobo Deluxe is an enhanced version of Akira Higuchi's game XKobo. A 2D 360 degree shooter, the objective is to destroy the core of all structures in each stage to advance while avoid the hectic barrage of projectiles.</description>
  </game>
  <game>
    <name>Hocoslamfy</name>
    <short>A paddleball-style game for the GCW Zero</short>
    <icon>game_128.png</icon>
    <link>hocoslamfy-od.opk</link>
    <preview>screenshot162.png</preview>
    <date>Tuesday, 25 Mar 2014</date>
    <author>Nebuleon</author>
    <portauthor/>
    <homepage>https://github.com/Nebuleon/hocoslamfy</homepage>
    <description>In this game, inspired by <i>Flappy Bird</i> by Dong Nguyen, you are a bee, and you have to steer yourself between columns that are made of bamboo.<br/> <br/> Controls are easy: any face button (A, B, X, Y) allows the bee to rise, and you can press A to start a new game. You can play this game with just one hand, for example on the bus or train, or if you do not have two hands for any reason.</description>
  </game>
  <game>
    <name>Tile World</name>
    <short>Emulator of the popular puzzle game "Chip's Challenge".</short>
    <icon>game_128.png</icon>
    <link>tileworld.opk</link>
    <preview>tileworld.png</preview>
    <date>Saturday, 15 Mar 2014</date>
    <author>Dan Silsby (Senor Quack)</author>
    <portauthor/>
    <homepage>https://github.com/senquack/tileworld-for-handhelds</homepage>
    <description>Tile World is an open source emulator of Chip's Challenge, able to<br/> emulate both the original Atari Lynx version as well as the Microsoft<br/> Windows version. Chip's Challenge remains a popular game even today, <br/> despite having been introduced in 1989. Thousands of unique levels have <br/> been created by fans. <br/> <br/> My port for the GCW features many additional features Tile World lacks, <br/> including hand-shrunk graphics, alpha-blended sprite shadows, automatic <br/> handling of configuration files, automatic loading of last levelset played, <br/> and an over-30-minute musical soundtrack (by the chip musicians Am-Fm and <br/> Chaozz). <br/> <br/> After you've run the program once, the CHIPS.DAT file from the original game <br/> can be copied into the GCW's $HOME/.tworld/data/ folder. There is no need<br/> to do anything more, configuration files will be automatically created. This<br/> is a lot easier than playing with the original Tile World!</description>
  </game>
  <game>
    <name>openMSX</name>
    <short>MSX emulator.</short>
    <icon>emulator_128.png</icon>
    <link>openmsx-0.10.0.opk</link>
    <preview>openMSX-logo-128.png</preview>
    <date>Tuesday, 07 Jan 2014</date>
    <author>openMSX Team</author>
    <portauthor>mth</portauthor>
    <homepage>http://www.openmsx.org/</homepage>
    <description>MSX emulator with high accuracy and lots of features.</description>
  </game>
  <game>
    <name>Blockling</name>
    <short>You are a young blockling who must stack blocks!</short>
    <icon>game_128.png</icon>
    <link>blockling.opk</link>
    <preview>blockling_1.png</preview>
    <date>Monday, 30 Dec 2013</date>
    <author>Andrew Anderson</author>
    <portauthor/>
    <homepage>https://github.com/andmatand/blockling/tree/gcw0</homepage>
    <description>You are a young blockling who must stack blocks to reach the exit!<br/> <br/> Features:<br/> * 8-bit Color!<br/> * Multi-Level Undo<br/> * Custom Levels</description>
  </game>
  <game>
    <name>EDuke32</name>
    <short>Modern Duke Nukem 3D engine port.</short>
    <icon>game_128.png</icon>
    <link>eduke32.opk</link>
    <preview></preview>
    <date>Sunday, 29 Dec 2013</date>
    <author>Richard "TerminX" Gobeille, Pierre-Loup "Plagman" Griffais, Philipp "Helixhorned" Kutin and others</author>
    <portauthor>Artur "zear" Rojek</portauthor>
    <homepage>http://eduke32.com</homepage>
    <description>EDuke32 is an awesome, free homebrew game engine and source port of the classic PC first person shooter Duke Nukem 3D.<br/> <br/> Created by Duke4.net community leader Richard "TerminX" Gobeille and a team of elite ninja programmers including NVIDIA software engineer Pierre-Loup "Plagman" Griffais and Philipp "Helixhorned" Kutin (based on work by Todd Replogle/Ken Silverman/Jonathon Fowler/Matt Saettler), EDuke32 is the undeniable king of Duke Nukem 3D ports.<br/> <br/> EDuke32 is licensed under the GNU GPL and the BUILD license.<br/> <br/> Source code of the port available at: https://github.com/zear/eduke32<br/> <br/> Special thanks to hi-ban for the "missing data" image.</description>
  </game>
  <game>
    <name>SuperTux</name>
    <short>Platform jump and run game, starring Tux.</short>
    <icon>game_128.png</icon>
    <link>supertux.opk</link>
    <preview>supertux2.png</preview>
    <date>Tuesday, 24 Dec 2013</date>
    <author>Tobias Glaesser, Bill Kendrick</author>
    <portauthor>Dmitry Smagin</portauthor>
    <homepage>https://github.com/dmitrysmagin/supertux</homepage>
    <description>SuperTux is a classic 2D jump'n run sidescroller game in a style similar to the original Super Mario games, covered under the GPL.</description>
  </game>
  <game>
    <name>Sparrow C4A Manager</name>
    <short>A Compo4All Manager</short>
    <icon>application_128.png</icon>
    <link>Sparrow-C4A-Manager.opk</link>
    <preview>sparrow_c4a_manager.png</preview>
    <date>Sunday, 15 Dec 2013</date>
    <author>Ziz</author>
    <portauthor/>
    <homepage>http://github.com/theZiz/Sparrow-C4A-Manager</homepage>
    <description>A Manager for the Compo4All online highscore system from skeezix. Use it to create an account for submitting scores or looking at online highscores.<br/> <br/> An Internet connection is required!<br/> <br/> List of compatible titles:<br/> * Puzzletube</description>
  </game>
  <game>
    <name>MazezaM</name>
    <short>Puzzle game involving movable blocks.</short>
    <icon>game_128.png</icon>
    <link>mazezam.opk</link>
    <preview>mazezam_v10_5.png</preview>
    <date>Sunday, 08 Dec 2013</date>
    <author>alekmaul</author>
    <portauthor/>
    <homepage>http://www.portabledev.com</homepage>
    <description>You are trapped in Mazezam!<br/> <br/> You have to escape on the right by pushing rows of blocks left and right. You can retry a level by pressing SELECT, but this will cost you a life...<br/> <br/> Good luck!</description>
  </game>
  <game>
    <name>Picodrive</name>
    <short>Megadrive / 32X / MegaCD emulator</short>
    <icon>emulator_128.png</icon>
    <link>PicoDrive.opk</link>
    <preview>picodrive_new.png</preview>
    <date>Wednesday, 27 Nov 2013</date>
    <author>notaz</author>
    <portauthor>pcercuei</portauthor>
    <homepage>https://github.com/notaz/picodrive</homepage>
    <description>Picodrive is an emulator for the SEGA Megadrive, 32X and MegaCD consoles.</description>
  </game>
  <game>
    <name>Sqrxz 2</name>
    <short>Two seconds until death!</short>
    <icon>game_128.png</icon>
    <link>sqrxz2-v.latest-gcwzero.opk</link>
    <preview>sqrxz2.png</preview>
    <date>Sunday, 24 Nov 2013</date>
    <author>Retroguru</author>
    <portauthor>Artur "zear" Rojek</portauthor>
    <homepage>http://www.sqrxz.de/</homepage>
    <description>Sqrxz 2 is a Jump’n'Run which requires a sharp mind and fast reflexes, high frustration is guaranteed.<br/> <br/> Another day another journey... As living on planet Earth and its surrounding solar system seemed boring Sqrxz decided to check out another location in the universe. Just in case and to be extra careful he took a pocketful of emeralds with him to keep him in ready cash, but after starting his exciting journey he realised all his emeralds are suddenly missing! Retracing his steps Sqrxz notices mysterious creatures popping up all over the place to hinder him in his search… Oh what troublesome days... Help poor Sqrxz get back all his emeralds!</description>
  </game>
  <game>
    <name>Sabre</name>
    <short>Flight simulator with fighter planes of the Korean War era.</short>
    <icon>game_128.png</icon>
    <link>sabre.opk</link>
    <preview>screenshot008.png</preview>
    <date>Sunday, 24 Nov 2013</date>
    <author>Dan Hammer</author>
    <portauthor>Artur "zear" Rojek</portauthor>
    <homepage>https://github.com/zear/sabre</homepage>
    <description>Sabre is a flight simulator focusing on the older jets and piston-engined fighters of the Korean War / Cold War era.<br/> Featured is the classic North American F-86 SabreJet, which engaged the nimble MiG-15 in the skies over Korea.<br/> Also included are the F-84 ThunderJet, the F-51 Mustang, and the Yak-9.<br/> All of the planes in the game are can be flown by the player as well as the computer pilots.</description>
  </game>
  <game>
    <name>Spartak Chess</name>
    <short>Spartak Chess is a chess game based on the Stockfish engine.</short>
    <icon>game_128.png</icon>
    <link>spartak-chess.opk</link>
    <preview>spartak.png</preview>
    <date>Wednesday, 06 Nov 2013</date>
    <author>djdron</author>
    <portauthor>Artur "zear" Rojek</portauthor>
    <homepage>https://github.com/zear/Spartak-Chess/</homepage>
    <description>Chess game based on the Stockfish v1.8 engine. Designed with mobile devices in mind.<br/> <br/> Controls:<br/> * D-PAD/analog - move highlighted cell (select piece or cell to move)<br/> * A - take piece/make move<br/> * B - cancel move<br/> * SELECT - enter menu</description>
  </game>
  <game>
    <name>Stringrolled</name>
    <short>Help a cat and a princess escape a castle.</short>
    <icon>game_128.png</icon>
    <link>stringrolled.opk</link>
    <preview>stringrolled.png</preview>
    <date>Sunday, 03 Nov 2013</date>
    <author>Logicow</author>
    <portauthor>senquack, Surkow, hi-ban, Artur "zear" Rojek</portauthor>
    <homepage>https://github.com/zear/stringrolled</homepage>
    <description>A cat and a princess (actually, and a ball) are going to escape a castle in this epic platformer title.<br/> <br/> The game involves puzzle elements, which the characters need to solve by working together.</description>
  </game>
  <game>
    <name>Griffon Legend</name>
    <short>An action RPG with screen-to-screen map.</short>
    <icon>game_128.png</icon>
    <link>griffon.opk</link>
    <preview>gr_legend.png</preview>
    <date>Friday, 11 Oct 2013</date>
    <author>Daniel 'Syn9' Kennedy, music by David Turner</author>
    <portauthor>Dmitry Smagin</portauthor>
    <homepage>https://github.com/dmitrysmagin/griffon_legend</homepage>
    <description>The Griffon Legend is an action RPG with screen-to-screen map. It features an original storyline and design made in 16-bit style RPG's of SNES/GENESIS era. The map contains several locations with villages, woods and castles, as well as multiple enemies to defeat and secret spells to learn.</description>
  </game>
  <game>
    <name>REminiscence</name>
    <short>Flashback engine reimplementation.</short>
    <icon>game_128.png</icon>
    <link>REminiscence.opk</link>
    <preview></preview>
    <date>Sunday, 06 Oct 2013</date>
    <author>Gregory Montoir (Cyx)</author>
    <portauthor>Elwing</portauthor>
    <homepage>https://github.com/ElwingGit/GCW0_REminiscence</homepage>
    <description>About:<br/> <br/> REminiscence is a Flashback engine reimplementation. As a cinematic platformer, Flashback features gameplay similar to that of 1989's Prince of Persia. Each level spans a large number of non-scrolling screens, nearly all of which feature multiple levels of altitude �" requiring the player character Conrad to jump, grab onto ledges, climb, use elevators, and drop onto lower levels. Conrad exhibits realistic human running speed and jumping ability, as well as realistic weakness �" he will die if he falls from too great a height.<br/> <br/> Conrad also carries a pistol with unlimited ammunition, a force shield (which absorbs a certain number of shots before needing recharging), and a portable force field (which can act as a barrier to deflect enemies' laser shots).<br/> <br/> As Conrad progresses through the game's seven levels, he is increasingly presented with spatial puzzles, requiring the player to discover how to guide him toward his destination. Late in the game, Conrad receives a teleportation device, and is able to progress by throwing the device into areas that he would otherwise be unable to reach.<br/> <br/> Game data:<br/> <br/> Flashback is not a free game, to be able to play it with this new engine you need<br/> the game data. This port should support all the file formats supported by Cyx's<br/> REminiscence.<br/> <br/> * Required data:<br/> The DOS PC game data, both the floppy and the CD-ROM versions are supported.<br/> <br/> *optional datas:<br/> The Amiga mod files can be added to get music during the cinematics.<br/> The SegaCD speech file (voice.vce) for in-game speech.<br/> <br/> Installation:<br/> <br/> REminiscence by default will create a folder for the data and the savefile if it did not exist before. Thus you can either:<br/> 1) copy the opk on the GCW0<br/> 2) run the opk once<br/> 3) copy the datafile in "/usr/local/home/.REminiscence/data"<br/> 4) start the opk again and enjoy the game<br/> or:<br/> 1) copy the opk on the GCW0<br/> 2) create the folder and copy the datafile in "/usr/local/home/.REminiscence/data"<br/> 3) start the opk again and enjoy the game<br/> <br/> Key Mapping:<br/> <br/> This port offers two different key mapping layouts:<br/> <br/> Type A:<br/> Arrow Keys move Conrad<br/> A use the current inventory object<br/> B talk / use / run / shoot<br/> X draw gun<br/> Y display the inventory<br/> Start display the options<br/> <br/> Type B:<br/> Arrow Keys move Conrad<br/> A draw gun<br/> B use the current inventory object<br/> X talk / use / run / shoot<br/> Y display the inventory<br/> Start display the options<br/> <br/> you can change the mapping used through the main menu, in the "info" submenu.<br/> <br/> Credits:<br/> <br/> - Gregory Montoir of course and all the people who helped him with the original REminiscence.<br/> - Hi-Ban, who provided great icon to replace the copyright infringing icon I had before.<br/> - All GCW0 team for their nice toolchain, their testing done, the GCW0 itself and the nice repo.</description>
  </game>
  <game>
    <name>Unnamed Monkey Game (exclusive preview)</name>
    <short>A retro platformer.</short>
    <icon>game_128.png</icon>
    <link>umg-gcw-exclusive-preview-0.4.opk</link>
    <preview>umg.png</preview>
    <date>Thursday, 03 Oct 2013</date>
    <author>Artur "Zear" Rojek, Andreas "Harteex" Bjerkeholt, Thorin "Topy" Hopkins, Daniel "Danik" Kvarfordt</author>
    <portauthor/>
    <homepage>http://www.unnamedmonkeygame.com/</homepage>
    <description>UMG is an oldschool platformer. By oldschool we mean 80s, Grey Brick style, but without the blur. "So what" you might say, seeing as everybody seems to be doing that right now. We don't do gimmicks, physics engines, or flashy colourful graphics. Actually, we don't do colours at all. Instead our focus is on gameplay. There are a lot of potentially good platform games out there that fail miserably due to badly thought through leveldesign, annoying gimmicks, or because the jump height of your character is just a few pixels off what you think it should be. So our biggest focus is on getting it just right. If you fail at UMG, you will know it is because you made a mistake, not because of the game not doing what you expected it to.</description>
  </game>
  <game>
    <name>Vectoroids</name>
    <short>Clone of Asteroids</short>
    <icon>game_128.png</icon>
    <link>vectoroids-1.1.opk</link>
    <preview>_vectoroid.png</preview>
    <date>Friday, 13 Sep 2013</date>
    <author>Bill Kendrick (http://www.newbreedsoftware.com/)</author>
    <portauthor>darth_llamah (with help from mth, pcerceui and JohnnyOnFlame)</portauthor>
    <homepage>https://github.com/darth-llamah/vectoroids</homepage>
    <description>"Vectoroids" is a clone of the classic arcade game "Asteroids" by Atari.<br/> <br/> Your objective is to maneuver a space ship within a field of asteroids, and shoot them into smaller and smaller pieces, eventually destroying them completely.<br/> <br/> Keybindings<br/> <br/> D-pad left/right, Joystick left/right: turn the ship<br/> D-pad up, Joystick up: throttle<br/> A: shoot<br/> X: respawn<br/> Select in game: quit to menu<br/> Select in menu: quit to gmenu2x</description>
  </game>
  <game>
    <name>Apricots</name>
    <short>A 2D arcade plane shooter.</short>
    <icon>game_128.png</icon>
    <link>apricots.opk</link>
    <preview>apricots.png</preview>
    <date>Sunday, 01 Sep 2013</date>
    <author>Mark Snellgrove, Mark Harman, Judebert, Artur "zear" Rojek</author>
    <portauthor>Artur "zear" Rojek</portauthor>
    <homepage>https://github.com/zear/apricots</homepage>
    <description>From the author:<br/> "Apricots is a game I've been writing in my spare time.<br/> Despite the name, it has nothing to do with apricots.<br/> It's a game where you fly a little plane around the<br/> screen and shoot things and drop bombs on enemy targets,<br/> and it's meant to be quick and fun."</description>
  </game>
  <game>
    <name>DOSBox 0.74</name>
    <short>Dos emulator</short>
    <icon>emulator_128.png</icon>
    <link>dosbox.opk</link>
    <preview>db_op_keyb.png</preview>
    <date>Monday, 12 Aug 2013</date>
    <author>DOSBox team</author>
    <portauthor>Dmitry Smagin</portauthor>
    <homepage>https://github.com/dmitrysmagin/dosbox-gcw0</homepage>
    <description>DOSBox emulates CPU:286/386 realmode/protected mode, Directory FileSystem/XMS/EMS, Tandy/Hercules/CGA/EGA/VGA/VESA graphics, a SoundBlaster/Gravis Ultra Sound card for excellent sound compatibility with older games...</description>
  </game>
  <game>
    <name>Last Mission</name>
    <short>Screen-by-screen maze shooter game with a huge labyrinth.</short>
    <icon>game_128.png</icon>
    <link>last-mission.opk</link>
    <preview>lastmission_new.png</preview>
    <date>Tuesday, 30 Jul 2013</date>
    <author>Pedro Ruiz (OperaSoft)</author>
    <portauthor>Dmitry Smagin, Alexey Pavlov, Mark Braga (music)</portauthor>
    <homepage>https://github.com/dmitrysmagin/last-mission</homepage>
    <description>You control a tank-like robot which can be divided in two: you rotate caterpillar and head-cannon, and the head part can fly off on its own. However, the head can only survive separately for a short amount of time, and your restart position is dictated by the <br/> location of the body, even if the head has moved forward through further screens. </description>
  </game>
  <game>
    <name>SMS_SDL</name>
    <short>Sega Master System &amp; Game Gear emulator</short>
    <icon>emulator_128.png</icon>
    <link>sms_sdl.opk</link>
    <preview>sms_sdl.png</preview>
    <date>Sunday, 14 Jul 2013</date>
    <author>Gregory Montoir</author>
    <portauthor>joyrider (dingux), mth, Dmitry Smagin (adaptation for GCW0)</portauthor>
    <homepage>https://github.com/darth-llamah/sms_sdl</homepage>
    <description>Usage:<br/> <br/> Select+start = menu<br/> <br/> Game Gear uses the start key, while Master System uses the B key to start. DPAD, B/A are the ingame keys and with the Y button you can take a screenshot. L is quicksave and R is quickload.<br/> <br/> Originally ported to Dingux by dosfish, modified by joyrider (aka Willems Davy).<br/> Adaptation for GCW0- mth with additional patches by d_smagin<br/> Icon by starvingartist (http://starvingartist.deviantart.com/)<br/> Compilation and packaging- darth_llamah</description>
  </game>
  <game>
    <name>HWTest</name>
    <short>Button and sound hardware test.</short>
    <icon>application_128.png</icon>
    <link>hwtest_20121208.opk</link>
    <preview>hwtest.png</preview>
    <date>Tuesday, 09 Jul 2013</date>
    <author>clach04</author>
    <portauthor/>
    <homepage>https://bitbucket.org/clach04/hwtest/</homepage>
    <description>This is a PyGame based test tool. Currently tests:<br/> <br/> * buttons<br/> * first analog joystick (stick 0), on GCW0 analog nub<br/> * second analog joystick (stick 1), on GCW0 motion sensor, NOTE requires gsensor OPK to have been installed and started<br/> * simple screen test<br/> * sound <br/> <br/> Button testing automatically stops after 10 seconds if no button/joystick has been moved in the last 10 secs and audio testing starts.<br/> <br/> Analog stops testing after 10 secs of no joystick movement or by pressing SELECT (Escape). Deadzone can be adjusted in analog test mode with D-pad (cursor keys) and A, B, X, and Y buttons.<br/> <br/> Sound can be tested alone by running with a parameter, e.g. "python hardware_test.py sound".</description>
  </game>
  <game>
    <name>Dink Smallwood</name>
    <short>Help a boy become a man on this RTSoft RPG.</short>
    <icon>game_128.png</icon>
    <link>freedink.opk</link>
    <preview>dink.png</preview>
    <date>Tuesday, 09 Jul 2013</date>
    <author>Robinson Technologies</author>
    <portauthor>Johnny On Flame</portauthor>
    <homepage>http://www.rtsoft.com/pages/dink.php</homepage>
    <description>Released in 1998 by Robinson Technologies, the game became a cult hit ever since. Guide Dink Smallwood, pig farmer turned hero in his quest to become a man in this Zelda-esque game and defeat the greater evil!</description>
  </game>
  <game>
    <name>Astro Lander</name>
    <short>A lunar lander game.</short>
    <icon>game_128.png</icon>
    <link>AstroLander.opk</link>
    <preview>astrolander.png</preview>
    <date>Tuesday, 09 Jul 2013</date>
    <author>Flatmush</author>
    <portauthor/>
    <homepage>Not available</homepage>
    <description>Control the velocity and altitude of your lunar landing module, while you avoid the mountain ridges and attempt to land on the designated spot. Don't forget to look after the fuel level.</description>
  </game>
  <game>
    <name>Biniax 2</name>
    <short>An action-puzzle game.</short>
    <icon>game_128.png</icon>
    <link>Biniax2.opk</link>
    <preview>biniax2.png</preview>
    <date>Tuesday, 09 Jul 2013</date>
    <author>Jordan Tuzsuzov</author>
    <portauthor>Harteex</portauthor>
    <homepage>http://mordred.dir.bg/biniax/index2.html</homepage>
    <description>Biniax 2 is a game of logic and reaction.<br/> The 3 game modes allow you to play against the time, pure tactical play or challenge with a friend in a multiplayer game.<br/> Biniax series are also child-friendly games: no kills, no violence, no weapons.</description>
  </game>
  <game>
    <name>Block Rage</name>
    <short>Highly addictive falling blocks game.</short>
    <icon>game_128.png</icon>
    <link>blockrage.opk</link>
    <preview>blockrage.png</preview>
    <date>Tuesday, 09 Jul 2013</date>
    <author>Jiri Svoboda</author>
    <portauthor>Artur "zear" Rojek</portauthor>
    <homepage>http://blockrage.sourceforge.net/</homepage>
    <description>Block Rage is falling blocks game with a 2-player hoseat mode, detailed graphics and animated plasmatic backgrounds. It is a remake of the awesome DOS classic Xixit.</description>
  </game>
  <game>
    <name>Free Doom</name>
    <short>A GPL licensed first person shooter.</short>
    <icon>game_128.png</icon>
    <link>oda_freedoom.opk</link>
    <preview>freedoom.png</preview>
    <date>Tuesday, 09 Jul 2013</date>
    <author>the Freedoom project</author>
    <portauthor>Johnny On Flame</portauthor>
    <homepage>http://www.nongnu.org/freedoom</homepage>
    <description>The Freedoom project aims to create a complete Doom-based game which is Free Software.<br/> <br/> Explore an abandoned base full of zombies and other monsters. Kill them all or die trying.<br/> <br/> This particular port uses the Odamex engine.</description>
  </game>
  <game>
    <name>Mine Sweeper</name>
    <short>A mine clearing puzzle game.</short>
    <icon>game_128.png</icon>
    <link>MineSweeper.opk</link>
    <preview>minesweeper.png</preview>
    <date>Tuesday, 09 Jul 2013</date>
    <author>Flatmush</author>
    <portauthor/>
    <homepage>Not available</homepage>
    <description>Move across the board and uncover the fields. A number on a tile informs you about the amount of mines hidden in the adjacent tiles. Flag the tiles you think have a bomb on them. Unmine the whole board to win.<br/> It's the old classic!</description>
  </game>
  <game>
    <name>SameGoo</name>
    <short>SameGame style puzzle game.</short>
    <icon>game_128.png</icon>
    <link>SameGoo.opk</link>
    <preview>samegoo.png</preview>
    <date>Tuesday, 09 Jul 2013</date>
    <author>Harteex</author>
    <portauthor/>
    <homepage>http://www.harteex.com/?page=samegoo</homepage>
    <description>SameGoo is a game of the SameGame concept. The goal is to get a high score. Selecting an object will clear that object and all connected objects of the same color.<br/> You cannot clear a single object, it must be connected to at least one other.<br/> If a gap occurs between columns of objects, then the right-most ones will be moved left.<br/> <br/> The more objects you clear at once, the higher score you will get. You will also get a 1000 score bonus for clearing the whole board.</description>
  </game>
  <game>
    <name>Sqrxz 3</name>
    <short>Adventure for love.</short>
    <icon>game_128.png</icon>
    <link>sqrxz3-v.1.05r-gcw-zero.opk</link>
    <preview>sqrxz3.png</preview>
    <date>Tuesday, 09 Jul 2013</date>
    <author>Retroguru</author>
    <portauthor>Artur "zear" Rojek</portauthor>
    <homepage>http://www.sqrxz.de/sqrxz-3/</homepage>
    <description>Sqrxz 3 is a Jump'n'Run which will please the hardcore gamer amongst you. You need fast fingers and a fast brain.<br/> <br/> Sqrxz and his girlfriend were on a romantic adventure journey in a jungle somewhere here on our planet. All of a sudden Yve gets kidnapped by an evil power and Sqrxz is forced to collect dozens of shiny little rings to free her. The old ruins he has to explore are anything else than safe. Traps are spread all over the place… and… Sqrxz is not alone!<br/> <br/> Original Sqrxz made by Marcus Vesterlund and John Holmvall.</description>
  </game>
  <game>
    <name>Powder</name>
    <short>Graphical roguelike.</short>
    <icon>game_128.png</icon>
    <link>powder_117.opk</link>
    <preview>powder.png</preview>
    <date>Saturday, 06 Jul 2013</date>
    <author>Jeff Lait</author>
    <portauthor>Artur "zear" Rojek</portauthor>
    <homepage>http://www.zincland.com/powder</homepage>
    <description>To understand POWDER, you should first understand roguelikes. "Roguelike" is a term applied to a wide variety of games which share a common inspiration from the game Rogue. A non-exhaustive list of such games would be: ADOM, Nethack, Crawl, Diablo (I … II), Moria, and Angband. My apologies to the many excellent roguelikes I didn't list. What characterizes these games? The exact specifications are a matter of debate - indeed, I may receive hate mail for including Diablo - but I shall try to write a few:<br/> <br/> Tactical play. The unit of action is based on the individual adventurer. The game is not twitch oriented (like Quake, rewarding reflexes … well trained actions) nor is it strategy oriented (like Civilizations or Warcraft, requiring working on the large picture)<br/> Based in Hack and Slash. A roguelike isn't primarily about plot development or telling a story. It is about killing things and acquiring treasure.<br/> Random games. A roguelike is a dungeon crawler where no two games are the same. The maps are different, the items are different, there are no guaranteed win paths.<br/> Permadeath. You die, that is it. No restoring a savegame. Good roguelikes delete your save game after loading them. This is compensated by the replayability of the game.<br/> Complex interactions of properties. While the commands for a roguelike are simple, the potential interactions are not. My favourite example is equipping a silver ring as a weapon in order to damage a creature vulnerable to silver, but not one's other weapons. [Editor: This matches the Hack branch of the roguelike tree, not the Angband branch]<br/> Steam rolling monsters. If a critter is in your way, and weak, you shouldn't even notice it is there.</description>
  </game>
</games>
